Anthony Hien Vu

Full Stack Web Developer | Tech Lead

Contact

Address

Wentworthville, NSW, 2145

Phone

0452668725

Email

avu120@gmail.com

Portfolio

https://avu120.github.io/por folio

GitHub

https://aithub.com/AVu120

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/ir/anthony-hien-vu/

Skills

React

Excellent

Redux

Excellent

CSS/Modules/SASS/CSS-in-JS/CSS-in-HTML

Excellent

Full Stack Web Developer (with a strong preference for the frontend) and Tech Lead. I have also worked in DevOps (I have 2 AWS associate certifications & experience building CICD pipelines). I've also worked in QA (including writing automated end to end and API tests).

Work History

2021-09 – now

Senior Full Stack Web Developer | Tech Lead

Checkbox, Sydney, NSW

- Architected full-stack technical design for new features and user workflows.
- Trained/mentored junior engineers in React/frontend best practices (in areas like performance optimization and testing).
- Designed long-term testing strategy.
- Created JIRA tickets for required work and delegated to team members.
- Influenced future product feature roadmap.
- Implemented agile team processes to reduce process ambiguity and improve consistency of team output.
- Implemented automated end to end and API tests (in CypressJS) & added them to CICD pipeline.
- Implemented migration from JavaScript to TypeScript on the frontend.
- Implemented mass-adoption of unit/integration tests on the frontend with Jest and React Testing Library.
- Added many new and old UI components to the Storybook.js design system.
- Built new React UI with Redux in the primary B2B application.
- Built new and modified existing Go (Golang) APIs.

2021-03 – 2021-09

Full Stack Web Developer

oOh!media, Sydney, NSW

- Built new features into internal React & Redux applications.
- Gave comprehensive React training to mid & seniorlevel engineers.

React Component Testing Automated E2E & API Testing UI Design Systems (E.g. Excellent **Excellent** Node/Express Excellent **Building REST APIs** Excellent **AWS** Very Good **SQL** Databases Very Good NoSQL Databases Very Good Web Sockets

Figma (Design/Wireframe

Building GraphQL APIs

• Built evergreen internal UI design system using Storybook.js.

 Built new features in Node - Express.js/GraphQL servers.

- Built new features in python API servers.
- Made configuration changes in AWS services like SQS, Lambda and EC2.
- Made configuration changes to Concourse CICD pipelines.

2018-08 - **Full S** 2021-02

Full Stack Web Developer

Telstra, Sydney, NSW

- Performed full stack development of a Telstra
 enterprise web application with thousands of
 internal users utilizing the MERN (MongoDB, Express,
 React, Node) stack with redux. The primary feature
 of this application is a catalogue of charts displaying
 data from various sources. I built new features into
 this application every day. Some examples include
 allowing the users to query databases from within
 the application, automatically schedule user-written
 scripts against databases, set up monitoring &
 alarms, and many more. The application uses a
 microservices architecture and is deployed on AWS.
- Troubleshooted operational issues in AWS core services such as CloudWatch, EC2, ECR and DocumentDB.
- Containerized many applications using Docker.
- Configured NGINX reverse-proxies to forward requests to various servers/micro-services-in-dockercontainers.
- Wrote unit tests using Jest.js, Enzyme.js and React Testing Library.
- Set up CICD pipelines using Atlassian's Bamboo platform.
- Documented many APIs using Swagger/OpenAPI specification.

2017-02 -2018-05

Good

IT Consultant

KPMG, Sydney, NSW

VueJS Good Languages Excellent Excellent Java

Education

2013-02 -2016-11

Bachelor of Science: Engineering

Sydney University - Sydney, NSW

Certifications

2021-07

AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate

2021-03

AWS Certified Developer - Associate

Interests

- Improving developer experience (I'm quite proactive on updating documentation and innovating with new team processes)
- Mentoring
- Leadership
- System architecture
- Web app performance
- UX Design
- Accessibility
- DevOps/Cloud/Serverless
- Al/Machine-Learning
- Staying up to date with the latest technologies, trends, and best practices.

Hobbies

- Ice Skating
- Cricket
- Hiking/Running
- Reading
- Tech Meetups
- Traveling